Deian Radev

Northern Virginia https://www.linkedin.com/in/deianradev

Profile

Frontend Tech Lead with 16+ years of experience seeking a UI leadership position. Keen on user experience and design; writing reusable object oriented code. Practices Agile methodology.

Preferred Technologies

Angular & Angular Material



Javascript, Typescript, ES6



HTML5



Bootstrap 4



CSS3



Nodeis



Git



RxJs



Education

B.Sc. Information Systems Virginia Commonwealth University

Citizenship & Clearance

U.S. Citizen

Key Highlights

UI Tech Lead Using Agile Practices 10 years of Angular experience Frontend Architect for multiple applications Reactive programming using RxJS

Work Experience

Dev Technology

2023 - present

Senior Frontend Developer

 Implement new UI features and maintain existing web interfaces for US Customs and Border Protection

GXM Consulting

2020 - 2023

Frontend Tech Lead

- Architect & develop dashboard UI for U.S. Government client
- Technology stack: Angular, Angular Material, HTML5, CSS3, Gitlab, Karma & Jasmine unit testing
- Upgrading application to latest Angular version 14

Mastercard - Perficient

2019 - 2020

Frontend Developer

- Develop frontend web portal UI for micro loans application
- Technology stack: Angular, Angular Material, Bootstrap 4, HTML5, CSS3, RESTful APIs, Cloud Foundry, Git, Karma & Jasmine unit testing

DHS, U.S. Customs & Border Protection - Unisys

2018-2019

Frontend Developer

- Develop frontend UI for mobile payment processing app
- Technology stack: Angular 6, Angular Material, Bootstrap 3, HTML5, CSS3, RESTful APIs; Karma & Jasmine unit testing

Department Of Justice - Leidos

2015 - 2018

Frontend Developer

 Developed frontend UI for litigation software using AngularJS, RESTful APIs, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery and D3 visualizations

Food And Drug Administration - Alethix

2014 - 2015

Frontend Developer

 Developed mobile web apps using AngularJS, HTML5, CSS, Google Maps Engine; visual dashboards and UIs using Kibana, ElasticSearch

Counterpointe Solutions

2011 - 2014

Web Applications Developer

 Developed back-end JavaEE web app; wrote MS SQL Server 2008 queries and stored procedures; created UI screens with HTML, CSS

JPMorgan Chase

2009 - 2011

Web Applications Developer

Created financial software using JSP, Java, HTML, and COTS product

Coventry Healthcare

2007 - 2008

Deployment Coordinator

 Planned and facilitated the successful deployment of software releases into QA and Production